Mss.Rec.181 Mss.Rec.181
American Philosophical Society
Morphological structure of Nisgha
1986-1987
Mss.Rec.181
American Philosophical Society
13.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic field recordings of the Nisgha (or Niska) language. Elicitation of a numbered list of words and phrases conducted by Linda Walsh with consultants Dorothy Doolan and Bertha Azak. Recorded from 1986 to 1987 in Vancouver, British Columbia.
13 sound cassettes (6 hr., 30 min.); analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Azak, Bertha
Doolan, Dorothy
Walsh, Linda G.
Conditions Governing Access
This material has access restritions. Please consult a curator for details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Linda Walsh in 1994. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Field notes, transcripts, and other related manuscript material are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Niska language; Sound recordings
- Series 1: Bertha Azak, Mss.Rec.181.1
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1-50, 1986-06-24; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:30; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Niska language; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 51-136, 1986-06-25; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:53; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 137-202, 1986-06-27; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:18; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 203-268, 1986-07-02; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:01; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 269-339, 1986-07-02; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:22; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 340-402, 1986-07-07; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:38; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 400-425, 1986-07-07; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:43; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 426-457, 469-490, 1986-07-08; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:23; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 491-555, 1986-07-09; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:54; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 458-468, 1986-07-08; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:39; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 556-587, 599, 1986-07-17; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:15; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 599-635, 1986-07-17; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 635-698, 1986-07-18; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:54; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 699-743, 1986-07-23; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:40; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 744-809, 1986-07-23; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:58; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 810-824, 1986-07-24; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:55; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 825-916, 1986-07-29; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:28; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 917-1010, 1986-08-05; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:43; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1011-1032, 1986-08-05; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:39; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1033-1117, 1986-08-12; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:45; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1118-1187, 1986-08-27; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:20; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1188-1208, 1986-09-05; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:47; Azak, Bertha; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1209-1255, 1986-09-05; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:47; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
    Human body--Terminology; Niska language; Vancouver (B.C.)
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1255-1281, 1986-11-13; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:45; Azak, Bertha; Walsh, Linda G.
- Series 2: Dorothy Doolan, Mss.Rec.181.2
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 1-63, 1986-09-09; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:22; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 64-105, 1986-09-12; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:20; Azak, Bertha; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 106-151, 1986-09-17; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:43; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 152-176, 1986-09-23; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:51; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 177-200, 1986-09-23; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:39; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 201-225, 1986-10-02; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 226-227, 229-257, 1986-10-21; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:43; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 258-307, 1986-12-02; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:18; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 308-355, 1986-12-11; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:07; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 356-364, 1986-12-11; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:12; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 365-414, 1987-01-23; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:43; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 415-467, 1987-01-29; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:39; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 468-526, 1987-02-10; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:46; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 527-547, 1987-02-19; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:47; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 548-584, 1987-02-19; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:17; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 585-619, 1987-02-26; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:18; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
    Scope and Contents note
    Recording cuts off in middle of sentence 619. Sentences 620-636 are in the transcript but not on recording.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 637-689, 1987-03-04; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:17; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 690-721, 729, 1987-03-12; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:06; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
    Sentences 722-728 do not exist on the recording or in the transcript due to misnumbering.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 730-733, 737-757, 1987-03-12; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:43; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
    Sentences 734-736 do not exist on the recording or in the transcript due to misnumbering.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 758-811, 1987-03-13; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:48; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 812-855, 1987-03-18; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:48; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 856-894, 1987-03-27; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:37; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 895-912, 1987-04-03; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:25; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 913-928, 1987-04-03; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:13; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 929-972, 1987-04-10; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:36; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.
  - Nisgha elicitation session: Sentences 973-1010, 1987-04-21; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:14; Doolan, Dorothy; Walsh, Linda G.